The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
♪ Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano ♪
The dreams I see are my secret
♪ Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano ♪
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
♪ Akai manto hira hira ♪
A red cape fluttering
♪ Uma o tobasu oujo ♪
Galloping on a horse—the princess
♪ Sore ga atashi ♪
That’s me!
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Ribon no kishi wa ♪
The Knight of the Ribbon,
♪ Honto wa hontto wa ♪
Truly, truly,
♪ Atashi nano sa ♪
It’s really me!
Nineteenth Episode
The Magic Pen
Magic Pen
Alright!
Next!
Hah!
Your Highness!
Here goes!
Bullseye!
All five hit!
They didn't hit the center, though.
Alright!
One more time!
There!
Nice!
All five right in the center!
Wait, no!
The ones in the center aren't mine!
Huh?
Could it be... hm?
Over there!
Who's there?!
Right!
Opal!
Go!
Hey!
Sapphire!
Who goes there!
You!
Oh, it's Prince Franz!
Sorry!
I wanted to meet you somewhere alone!
Feisty as ever, I see!
You tomboy princess!
I'm not a princess!
I told you, I'm a prince!
There's no one around!
You don't have to hide it from me!
Princess Sapphire!
Sapphire is a boy!
A boy!
No matter what anyone says, a boy!
Here!
Wait, isn't this a pen?!
Don't bring random stuff into this!
Never mind that, just take it!
Here!
Paper and ink!
So, you're a boy, right?
Then write Sapphire is a boy right here!
What on earth for?!
It's a magical pen!
Now, write what I told you!
"Sapphire is a boy."
You meant to write "Sapphire is a boy," right?
But take a close look at what you wrote!
"Sapphire is a girl!"
See?
You wrote girl yourself!
That's strange!
But I wrote boy!
One more time!
"Sapphire is a boy..."
"Sapphire is a girl!"
Why do I keep writing girl?!
Because you are a girl!
Sapphire, a great doctor gave me that magic pen!
You can't write lies with it!
Even the biggest liar can only write the truth with that pen!
You know, Sapphire, you're really charming!
It's true!
You're so spunky, and you're just as tough as any boy!
Plus, you have such a kind heart!
So kind, so very kind!
And the fact that you don't even realize it just makes you all the more charming!
I have a favor to ask of that kind Sapphire!
I want you to give that mysterious pen to the flaxen-haired girl!
A flaxen-haired girl?
I want to know!
How she really feels!
I'll never forget!
About the carnival where I danced with that flaxen-haired girl...
Young Franz... Is Sapphire that flaxen-haired girl?
Come on, please!
It's the favor of a lifetime!
Find the flaxen-haired girl and tell her to write a letter with this pen!
Why don't you look for her and ask her yourself?
I can't!
My uncle's been breathing down my neck lately!
I barely managed to sneak out of the castle today!
Prince Franz!
Prince Franz, you're making things very difficult for us!
Sneaking off to play in the neighboring kingdom...
His Majesty is looking for you!
Please come back!
Oh no!
They found me already!
All right, Sapphire, I'm counting on you!
Don't forget!
Goodbye!
Welcome back, Your Highness.
Oh dear, he's gone.
Haha, hiding in the secret room again.
Dressing up like a girl right about now.
Indeed, Lord Sapphire is actually a girl, after all.
I wonder if Franz still hasn't figured it out.
Maybe I'll write a letter to Franz.
From the girl with the flaxen hair...
Hey, this is writing all by itself!
The true identity of the girl with the flaxen hair is Sapphire.
The girl with the flaxen hair is a little bit in love with Prince Franz.
Oh dear, this is embarrassing!
I can't send a letter like this!
The prince is strong.
The princess is a woman.
This really is a strange pen.
I know! It'd be fun to see what's on other people's minds.
Ah, it's Nanny!
Alright...
Up to mischief again?
What is this pen?
Just write whatever comes to mind.
Go on.
Is that so?
"Lord Sapphire goes too far with his mischief, so I can't stand him."
Here.
May Lord Sapphire grow up healthy and strong.
Thank you, Nanny.
Just write down whatever is on your mind.
Well then: "Prince Sapphire is a splendid prince."
"Long live Silverland!"
That is what was on my mind.
Gum, chocolate, juice, and ice cream?
You must be really hungry.
Um, who's next?
Oh, sorry!
Oh, Prince Sapphire.
That poor peacock.
We must treat animals with kindness, you know.
Yes, yes.
So I won't forget, could you write that down here for me?
Yes, well then...
"Let us treat animals with kindness."
Here.
"I'll secretly kill this peacock and use it as a hat decoration."
Oh my, did I write that?
Knowing what people are really thinking is so much fun!
Though everyone thinks such awful things despite how they look.
Alright,
he's the one whose mind I want to read the most.
Ah, Prince Sapphire, what brings you here?
What are you thinking about right now?
Hmm, well,
I was wishing for Prince Sapphire to grow up strong and for Silverland
to prosper even more. Just something like that.
Wonderful!
As expected of Lord Nylon!
Write those words down right here!
With pleasure.
"Yes, scribble, scribble, scribble..."
Wait a minute...
Oh, my. Your Highness.
I'm sorry, the rest is...
What on earth is going on?
"Sapphire must be a girl."
"Someday I'll rip off her mask..."
I didn't write anything like that!
I don't know, I really don't!
"Tonight at midnight." That's as far as you wrote!
Nylon!
Don't give me that I don't know!
What on earth is happening at midnight tonight?!
I don't know.
I really have no...
Hey, wait!
Wait Nylon!
I won't wait!
I can't wait either!
I said wait!
Wait!
He doesn't know where he's going.
I'll cut him off!
Well, welcome, Prince Sapphire.
Grand Duke Duralumin, what are you planning to do at midnight tonight?
Write your answer on paper with this pen!
No, I shall tell you out loud.
You can just make up lies out loud!
Write it with this pen!
Unfortunately, I have an injury.
Then write with your left hand!
My left hand is also, unfortunately... As I said, I'll answer out loud.
You can say whatever you want out loud!
I don't want to hear your lies!
Boy, what a pain to bring out a magic pen.
No, wait, it's a wonderful pen.
With that, even Sapphire won't be able to lie.
I'll make sure she writes "I am a woman".
Oh!
Brilliant as always, Grand Duke Duralumin!
By the way, what about our plan for midnight?
Of course we're going through with it.
It'll be even more fun than the original plan.
One hour left until midnight.
What on earth are they up to?
How many minutes are left?
Ah, damn it! What happened?
Fire!
It won't open!
I have to get out of here, quick!
Fire!
Someone, help!
Guess we have no choice.
It's almost like they were waiting for this.
What are you doing?!
Quick, douse it with water!
Putting out the fire comes first... Leave it to me!
They didn't even bring water?!
I bet they're using the fire as cover to search my room.
Wait!
What kind of fire brigade doesn't bring water?!
What do you think you're doing?!
Interfering with firefighting is a serious crime.
Shut up!
You're fake firefighters!
Do you want this place to burn?
Don't blame us if the castle turns to ash.
It's spreading!
Stop it!
Get out of here!
How troublesome. Just leave it to us—or this axe might fly!
Why, you...
You're the ones who started the fire!
You've shown your true colors!
Hey!
Someone, help!
Hurry!
The fire brigade is here!
No water's coming out!
One!
So cold!
Thanks, Garigori!
You guys...
Hey!
Wait!
Give me a break!
Who is it?!
Your boss!
It's someone I can't bring myself to say, lend me paper and a pen. I'll write their name down.
Let's make them write it with the magic pen.
Come on!
Write it!
I got it!
Wait!
Well done!
Great job!
Even you guys can be useful once in a while.
I guess so.
Now it's as good as ours.
Tomorrow, I'll definitely tear off Sapphire's mask.
Does it still hurt?
Tink!
Where on earth is this?
It's Mr. Garigori's room.
There was a fire in Sapphire's room yesterday, so I rushed right over.
And then Sapphire passed out.
So, you took care of me the whole time?
N-No...
Thank you.
Is my secret room okay?
It's fine. No one will ever find it.
Ah, I'm so sleepy.
Ah, Oh, no!
The pen!
Where did that thief go?!
Sapphire, what happened to the pen?
It's something you were holding onto for Franz.
Yeah.
It was stolen during the fire last night.
That's a real problem.
I wonder what it is?
Look at them moving all those desks and chairs.
Your Highness!
Sorry, sorry.
What are they preparing for anyway?
Well...
I don't know the details, but it's supposedly a ceremony for the Prince's Oath.
The Prince's Oath?
Yes!
A ceremony?
The Prince's Oath, you say?
Of course I know what that is.
It's a ceremony where the prince writes down and proclaims an oath to devote his life to the nation.
Still, it hasn't been performed in nearly 200 years.
This ceremony was abolished two centuries ago, so why bring it back so suddenly...?
Prince Sapphire.
Grand Duke Duralumin is waiting for you in the main hall.
Duralumin?
What does he want?
I was only told that he wishes to see you.
All right.
I'll be right there.
Congratulations, Your Highness.
What's with all these over-the-top preparations?
Besides, why do I have to take the Prince's Oath anyway?
Your Highness, this is an important ancient ritual.
Indeed, indeed!
What exactly am I supposed to do?
It's quite simple.
On this paper, you write: "I am without a doubt the prince of this realm."
"From now on, I shall serve this kingdom as its prince."
That is all you must write.
Using that pen right there.
Oh, what a strange pen...
Is something wrong, Prince Sapphire?
No!
I just hate making such a big fuss over something so obvious.
Your Highness, your father approved of this ritual himself and stamped it with his official seal.
If you refuse, we'll make you do it by force.
It starts right at noon.
It's completely hopeless.
If I use that pen, it'll definitely write "Sapphire is a woman"!
Oh, I know! Maybe Prince Franz can help us.
He won't be able to do a thing.
Besides, there are only two hours left.
I can do it! I'll go to the neighboring kingdom.
Ah, Tink!
He'll never make it in time.
One hour left.
We're here to escort you.
Escort?
Out of the way!
It is time, Sapphire.
To the Great Hall, please.
Oh, what an oddball.
Prince, please take that seat.
Right over here.
No way!
Sapphire, what is the matter?
Throwing a tantrum during such an important ceremony is unacceptable.
Yes.
But... what happened?
You're awfully reserved for a prince.
Sapphire, hurry and take your seat.
Now, please take the pen.
Hurry up and write!
Hesitating will only make them suspect you're a girl.
Pull yourself together. Sapphire, take the pen.
It's no use.
Come on, fly faster, Oowashi-san!
Hurry, hurry!
Faster!
There's no time left!
Ah, I see it! The castle!
Oowashi-san, pull up to that window!
Tink, let's go!
I can't get down!
What's wrong, Prince Sapphire?
Is there some reason you can't take the oath?
You're not a girl, so stop dragging your feet!
It's no use...
Oh no!
Sapphire has the pen!
Oh, what do we do?
What are you talking about?
Times like this are when you should act like a man and knock 'em dead!
I can't think of any good ideas.
Should I go make a scene?
Yeah, please!
Hold it!
Over there!
This way, this way!
Alright, cut it!
Franz?
I'm Blanco, and I travel the world picking fights!
I heard Prince Sapphire is pretty strong in this kingdom, so I came to fight him.
Wh-What did you say?
Seize this fool!
Come on, Sapphire!
Sounds like fun. Let's do this!
If anyone gets in the way of this fight, they'll regret it!
Ugh, why did this guy have to butt in?
Here I go!
Hey, you tomboy.
Thank you, Prince Franz.
Hey, wait!
Hey, wait! Stop!
No way! Let me at 'em!
Hold on! Had enough already?!
Come here.
You're safe now.
Now I can sleep soundly.
Franz, that strange pen of yours caused quite a lot of trouble.
Sorry, sorry. I won't rely on something like this again.
Hey Franz, people say one thing and mean another, don't they?
Yeah. I wonder if that flaxen-haired girl lies, too.
No, I'm sure she's the one who tells the truth.
I'm sure you'll meet her soon.
Wait, really?
You reached her, right?
He still hasn't noticed.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen ♪
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
♪ Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen ♪
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
♪ Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo ♪
Even if demons come, even if storms arrive,
♪ tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai ♪
Our bonded hearts will never part.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP